He's the best there is! (Actually, he's the only one there is.)
Ace Ventura: Pet Detective is a comedy, mystery,
crime film directed by Tom Shadyac.
He's Ace Ventura: Pet Detective.
The Ace is on the case to find the Miami Dolphins'
missing mascot and quarterback Dan Marino.
He goes eyeball to eyeball with a man-eating shark, stakes out
the Miami Dolphins and woos and wows the ladies.
Whether he's undercover, under fire or underwater,
he always gets his man… or beast!
Ace Ventura, played by Jim Carrey.
Melissa Robinson, played by Courteney Cox.
Lt. Lois Einhorn, played by Sean Young.
Emilio, played by Tone Loc.
Dan Marino, played by Dan Marino.
Riddle, played by Noble Willingham.
Ace Ventura: Pet Detective is a 1994 American comedy film starring Jim Carrey as Ace Ventura, an animal
detective who is tasked with finding the abducted dolphin mascot of the Miami Dolphins football team.
The film is directed by Tom Shadyac, who wrote the
screenplay with Jack Bernstein and Carrey.
The film co-stars Courteney Cox, Tone Loc, Sean Young, and then–Miami Dolphins quarterback Dan
Marino and features a cameo appearance from death metal band Cannibal Corpse.
Morgan Creek Productions produced the film on a
budget of $15 million, and Warner Bros.
released the film on February 4, 1994.
It grossed $72.2 million in the United States and Canada and $35 million in
other territories for a worldwide total of $107.2 million.
It received generally unfavorable reviews from critics.
However, Carrey's performance led to the film having a
cult following among male adolescents.
In addition to launching Carrey's film career, it started a franchise, spawning the sequel film Ace Ventura: When Nature Calls (1995), the animated
television series Ace Ventura: Pet Detective (1995–2000), and later, standalone made-for-television sequel Ace Ventura Jr.: Pet Detective (2009).
The film explores themes of miami, florida, dolphin,
detective, human animal relationship, stupidity.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.